Vishal Pachpinde

Product Engineer

vi6hal@gmail.com • +91-8378975554

https://www.linkedin.com/in/vi6hal/ • https://github.com/n0tNoah

Summary

3.8+ years of experience with Python development with strong knowledge in system design patterns, SOLID & DRY principles, low-level design, and implementation.

Developed competency in the following areas:

Webservices, RESTfull architecture, micro-service architecture, Django Odoo, flask, CI/CD, Redis, RabbitMQ, ECS, S3, RDS ELB, SQS, Database optimizations

Thorough knowledge of UNIX/Linux platforms. Scripting experience with Shell, XML, JSON, Advanced SQLs, PL/SQLs, & Scrapy

Skills

Python • Django • Rest API • PostgreSQL • Docker • Amazon Web Services • Flask

Work Experience

Product Engineer Apr 2021 – present

Larsen & Toubro Infotech • Full-time

Pune, India

Technologies: Python • Django • Docker • Celery • Redis

Responsibilities

- Building Scalable, high-performance, well documented, and reliable REST API's with exceptional code quality and test coverage
- Taking ownership of multiple modules technology stacks right from the design and coding phase to deployment and post-release
- Implementation of CI/CD framework to rapidly support the development lifecycle of the platform
- Working with distributed systems, scaling, performance optimization, etc.- coming up with solutions on cross-cutting concerns (security, monitoring, caching, concurrency, etc)

Software Engineer

Feb 2019 - Apr 2021 • 2 yrs 2 mos

Kennovation Software Services • Full-time

Pune, India

Technologies: Odoo Python • Django • Continuous integration • Github • PostgreSQL

Responsibilities:

- Responsible for the techno-functional analysis of Customers Business, solving workflow challenges coming up with innovative and efficient solutions
- Strong Debugging skills with exposure to code analysis and profiling
- Automated Release Packaging using semver and CI/CD
- Developing Odoo modules with exposure to background processing, batch transactions, atomic transactions, JSONRPC & XML-RPC

Support Associate

Jan 2018 - Dec 2018 • 11 mos

Tech Mahindra • Full-time

Pune, India

Technologies: MySQL • Python • System administration

Responsibilities:

- System Administration for Vision21 (User Privilege management)
- Writing Scripts for database export using MySQL/python
- · Generating & Maintaining Knowledgebase

Projects

<u>Achristos</u> Dec 2021 – Jan 2022 • 1 mo

Technologies: Django • Python

Archistos invokes Heroku app's/ Lamda Functions (enabled with API gateway)every 30 minutes so they never go to sleep, hence reducing the number of cold starts.

Excavator Dec 2020 – Jan 2021 • 1 mo

Technologies: Python • Django • JavaScript

A tool that can be used for gathering information on a device, with the use of a redirect link,Lots of the information gathered can be used to create unique fingerprints that can be associated with users.

A faster and optimized implementation of the grabify IP logger with more responsiveness

Educations

Master's degree: Computer Science

Apr 2017 – May 2019 • 2 yrs 1 mo

University of Pune

Pune, India

Bachelor's degree: Computer Science

Apr 2014 – Apr 2017 • 3 yrs

University of Pune

Pune, India

Certifications & Awards

Python for DataScience - IBM	Oct 2019
Microsoft Certified Specialist - Microsoft	Apr 2012

Languages

English (Native or bilingual proficiency)

Hindi (Native or bilingual proficiency)